<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mnemosyne core_version="1" >
<category active="1">
 <name>ch1</name>
</category>
<category active="1">
 <name>ch2</name>
</category>
<item id="_0">
 <cat>ch1</cat>
 <Q>What is Machine Learning?</Q>
 <A>A subfield of AI that allows computers to learn</A>
</item>
<item id="_1">
 <cat>ch1</cat>
 <Q>How does machine learning work?</Q>
 <A>It infers properties of data, and then makes predictions based on those inferences.</A>
</item>
<item id="_2">
 <cat>ch1</cat>
 <Q>Are decision trees transparent?</Q>
 <A>Yes, you can see the logic behind the decision.</A>
</item>
<item id="_3">
 <cat>ch1</cat>
 <Q>Are neural networks transparent?</Q>
 <A>No, they work like a black box, not allowing you to see how the decision was made.
</A>
</item>
<item id="_4">
 <cat>ch1</cat>
 <Q>Can regression be considered a form of machine learning?</Q>
 <A>Yes</A>
</item>
<item id="_5">
 <cat>ch1</cat>
 <Q>What are some downsides of machine learning?</Q>
 <A>A machine can only generalize on data that has been seen, and only in limited ways.</A>
</item>
<item id="_6">
 <cat>ch1</cat>
 <Q>With small amounts of data, is machine learning accurate?</Q>
 <A>Not always, machine learning has the possibility of overgeneralizing based on a few small coorelations.</A>
</item>
<item id="_7">
 <cat>ch2</cat>
 <Q>What is collaborative filtering?</Q>
 <A>Basically, it is looking at a large set of people and finding smaller sets, similar to you. It then looks at the things they like and creates a ranked list of suggestions for you.</A>
</item>
<item id="_8">
 <cat>ch2</cat>
 <Q>For collaborative filtering purposes, how must the data be represented?</Q>
 <A>It must be mapped to numerical values.</A>
</item>
<item id="_9">
 <cat>ch2</cat>
 <Q>How can you map a system of star-based ratings?</Q>
 <A>As integers from 0-total number of stars</A>
</item>
<item id="_10">
 <cat>ch2</cat>
 <Q>How can you map a a boolean situation?</Q>
 <A>0 if they didn't do it
1 if they did do it.</A>
</item>
<item id="_11">
 <cat>ch2</cat>
 <Q>How can you map a dislike, like, neutral system?
</Q>
 <A>Usually with 

-1: dislike
0: neutral
1: like</A>
</item>
<item id="_12">
 <cat>ch2</cat>
 <Q>What naive data structure can you use to represent preferences?</Q>
 <A>Arrays of arrays.</A>
</item>
<item id="_13">
 <cat>ch2</cat>
 <Q>How do you measure alikeness for collaborative filtering?</Q>
 <A>You need to determine the "similarity score."</A>
</item>
<item id="_14">
 <cat>ch2</cat>
 <Q>How is a "simiarlity score" obtained?</Q>
 <A>Euclidean distance (naive), or Pearson correlation (better), among others.</A>
</item>
<item id="_15">
 <cat>ch2</cat>
 <Q>How does Euclidean distance work in theory?</Q>
 <A>You plot each preference against another on an axis, and calculate the distance between two user points.  This should be possible in multiple dimensions as well.</A>
</item>
</mnemosyne>
